JAMES CHIGOZIE ODUFU

 $+234~806-449-7094 \diamond jamezjaz@gmail.com \diamond LinkedIn \diamond GitHub \diamond Hackernoon \diamond Medium \diamond Portfolio \diamond Lagos, Nigeria$

SUMMARY

Vision-driven software professional with 1+ years of full-stack software development skills in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux. Strongly focusing on delivering actionable and exceptional results. Seeking full-time software development opportunity to utilize my skills and abilities in a value-driven company that offers professional growth.

SKILLS

Programming Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Database PostgreSQL, SQLite

Technologies Git, Postman, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, AWS S3, RSpec, Jest, React Testing Library, Linux

Domains Full-stack Engineering, Software Development, REST APIs

EXPERIENCE

Microverse Remote May 2020 - Present Mentor (Volunteer)

• Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

• Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

South Saharan Social Dev. Organization

Enugu, Nigeria Feb 2020 - Feb 2021 Data Entry Clerk

• Collected, stored, and utilized data effectively.

• Prepared source data and compiled information whilst collecting scientific data and samples.

Kizito Mobile Technologies

Lagos, Nigeria

Manager

Nov 2016 - Feb 2018

• Solved software problems by providing necessary information, installed new software whilst working closely with hardware engineers.

Community Secondary School, Nzashi

Ebonyi, Nigeria

Mathematics/Biology Teacher

June 2015 - May 2016

• Integrated various forms of technology constantly to improve students' comprehension of various concepts.

Stufflink Academy/Chris-Tech Computer School

Enugu, Nigeria

Computer Operator

Jan 2009 - Dec 2013

• Trained people on an array of software applications such as Appreciation, Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Publisher, Corel Draw, Internet Research, Photoshop, Fireworks, Dream Weaver.

PROJECTS

Book-Air-Tickets GitHub Link

- This is an application for booking airline tickets. Its back-end is an API built with Ruby on Rails.
- Built With: React, Redux, JavaScript, Axios, PropTypes, Redux-thunk, Bootstrap, Rails API.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Development Program, Microverse (Remote)

Feb 2020 - May 2021

Diploma, Web Design & Development, New Horizons (Lagos, Nigeria)

Mar 2017 - Sept 2017

BSc, Applied Microbiology, Enugu State University of Science & Technology (Enugu, Nigeria) 2010 - 2014